(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.1",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"subtitles": 8
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
Nekomata Okayu 2nd Live.
ぺるそにゃ〜りすぺくと
Nekomata Okayu 2nd Live:
Peru Sonnya Respect
2025.5.28 WED @ PIA ARENA MM
Attention
ご来場のお客様へ
To all visitors
演出の都合上、照明の点滅にご注意ください
Please be aware of flashing lights during the performance.
声出し応援OKです
Cheering loudly is OK.
二次販売グッズ: 応援セット
Secondary Sales Goods: Support Set
おにぎりTシャツ / おにぎりペンライトポーチ
Onigiri T-shirt / Onigiri Penlight Pouch
ぺるそにゃ〜エコバッグ / 缶バッジ / シュシュキーホルダー
アクリルスタンド / クッション
Peru Sonnya Eco Bag / Can Badge / Scrunchie Keyholder
Acrylic Stand / Cushion
Nekomata Okayu 2nd Live.
ぺるそにゃ〜りすぺくと
Nekomata Okayu 2nd Live:
Peru Sonnya Respect
Attention
ご来場のお客様へ
To all visitors
二次販売グッズ: 応援セット
Secondary Sales Goods: Support Set
おにぎりTシャツ / おにぎりペンライトポーチ
Onigiri T-shirt / Onigiri Penlight Pouch
ぺるそにゃ〜エコバッグ / 缶バッジ / シュシュキーホルダー
Peru Sonnya Eco Bag / Can Badge / Scrunchie Keyholder
2nd Live 記念グッズ
2nd Live Commemorative Goods
お祝いメッセージ
Congratulatory Messages
The concert will be starting soon.
演出の都合上、照明の点滅にご注意ください
Please be aware of flashing lights during the performance.
声出し応援OKです
Cheering loudly is ok.
応援セット
Support Set
おにぎりゃーTシャツ
Onigiri-ya T-shirt
ぺるそにゃーエコバッグ
Persona Eco-bag
Sponsor
ラーラーラー
La la la...
あ、こっちこっちこっち！
Ah, this way, this way, this way!
今日二人じゃないんですね。
There aren't two of us today, are there?
え？
Eh?
二人？
Two?
さっきの... ここで会った人たち。
The people... we met here just now.
心で...
In my heart...
「ラヴ・パレード」ORANGE RANGE
"Love Parade" by ORANGE RANGE
Joyしてこーぜ！
Let's go Joy!
JOYSOUND X1
Nekomata Okayu 2nd Live.
ぺるそにゃ～りすぺくと
Nekomata Okayu 2nd Live:
Personya Respect
開演までしばらくお待ちください
The concert will be starting soon.
Attention ご来場の皆様へ
Attention: To all visitors
演出の都合上、照明の点滅にご注意ください
Please be aware of flashing lights during the performance.
声出し応援OKです
Cheering loudly is OK.
応援セット ¥11,800
(おにぎりゃーいと / おにぎりゃーTシャツ / 他)
Support Set ¥11,800
(Onigirya Light / Onigirya T-shirt / etc.)
おにぎりゃーTシャツ ¥4,500
おにぎりペンライトポーチ ¥2,900
Onigirya T-shirt ¥4,500
Onigirya Penlight Pouch ¥2,900
ぺるそにゃーエコバッグ ¥2,300
シュシュキーホルダー ¥2,400
Personya Eco-bag ¥2,300
Scrunchie Key Holder ¥2,400
猫又おかゆ 2nd Live ぺるそにゃ～りすぺくと
Nekomata Okayu 2nd Live 'Personya Respect'
Attention ご来場のお客様へ
Attention: To all visitors
演出の都合上、照明の点滅にご注意ください。
Please be aware of flashing lights during the performance.
声出し応援 OK です
Cheering loudly is OK.
本日は、猫又おかゆ 2nd Live
Thank you all for coming to Nekomata Okayu's
ぺるそにゃ～りすぺくとにご来場いただき、ありがとうございます！
2nd Live 'Personya Respect' today!
めっちゃ盛り上がってくれてるじゃん。
You guys are really fired up!
え、みんな、1足す1はー？
Hey everyone, what's 1 plus 1?
にー！
Two!
あはははは！いいね。今日ラグないね。
Ahahaha! Nice. No lag today.
はい、もぐもぐおかゆです。こんばんは。
Yes, this is Mogu Mogu Okayu. Good evening.
こんばんはー！
Good evening!
最後までライブを楽しんでいただくために、いくつかご案内させていただきます。
In order for everyone to enjoy the live until the end, I have a few announcements.
いい返事。
Good response.
公演中の撮影、録音、録画機材の使用は固くお断りいたします。
Photography, recording, and the use of recording equipment during the performance are strictly prohibited.
館内は禁煙となっております。喫煙はご遠慮ください。
The venue is non-smoking. Please refrain from smoking.
万が一、具合が悪くなってしまった場合は、無理をせず、近くのスタッフへお知らせください。
In the unlikely event that you feel unwell, please don't push yourself and notify a nearby staff member.
会場内でのモッシュ、ダイブ、ステージに物を投げ込むなど、
Moshing, diving, and throwing objects onto the stage are
他の皆に迷惑になったり、公演を妨げる行為は一切禁止です。
strictly prohibited, as they may disturb others or obstruct the performance.
ルールを守って盛り上がってくださいね。
Please follow the rules and have a great time!
はーい！
Okay!
いえーい。
Yay.
また、本公演は映像配信および写真撮影用のカメラが会場内に入り、
Also, cameras for video distribution and photography will be in the venue today,
客席が映り込む場合があります。
and the audience seats may be shown.
これらの映像や写真はプロモーションなどに使用される可能性がありますので、
Please be aware that these videos and photos may be used
あらかじめご了承ください。
for promotions and other purposes.
ここまでの影ナレ、実は振りがなをね、付けてもらったので、スラスラ読めてるでしょ？
Actually, I had furigana added to this pre-show announcement, so I'm reading it quite smoothly, right?
おー！
Oh!
あ、ありがとうございます。
Ah, thank you.
またライブのハッシュタグは #おかゆセカンド です。
The hashtag for the live is #OkayuSecond.
ハッシュタグを使ってたくさん盛り上げてくれると嬉しいな。
I'd be happy if you could help hype it up using the hashtag.
いえーい！
Yay!
お願いします。
Please do.
それでは、開演までもう少しです。
Well then, it's not long now until the show starts.
待ちに待った声出しありのセカンドライブ。
Our long-awaited second live with cheering allowed.
おにぎりゃーの声をいっぱい聞かせてね！
Let me hear plenty of your voices, Onigiri-ya!
おかゆ！おかゆ！
Okayu! Okayu!
全然いらないじゃんか
I don't need it at all, do I?
分かってくれないじゃんか
You don't understand it at all, do you?
真っ当じゃないなって
That it's not right...
お前はしないけど
You wouldn't say that, though.
全然笑えないじゃんか
I can't laugh at all, can I?
面白くなりもしないじゃんか
It's not getting interesting at all, is it?
ああ こんなもんかって
Ah, so this is it...
よかれは期待か
Was that well-meant expectation?
そもそも話君のこととか
To begin with, about you...
求めてることとか分からないんだ
Or what you're seeking, I just don't know.
泥々になるまでに混んだ感情
Emotions crowded until they turn to mud.
火傷しちゃうくらいアッチアッチ
Hot enough to leave a burn.
笑顔に甘えてるんじゃないの
Aren't you just riding on my smile?
優しさに溶かされてるんじゃないの
Aren't you being melted by my kindness?
答え合わせじゃなくて
It's not about checking for answers...
たまに思うだけ気にしないで
I just think it sometimes, so don't worry.
ようこそアリーナ！
Welcome to the arena!
あかんべで忘れましょう
Let's forget it with an 'Akanbe'.
正解はいらないのよ
I don't need the correct answer.
いいよ いいよ
It's fine, it's fine.
押し殺したげちゃうわ
I'll stifle it for you.
あかんべを覚えたら
Once you've learned 'Akanbe',
目一杯のドキドキしよう
Let's make our hearts pound to the max.
いいよ いいよ
It's fine, it's fine.
もっといい子になれたら開けましょう
If you can be a better kid, let's open up.
知りもしないくせにわかったふり
Pretending to know when you don't at all.
それで好きだなんて面白いわ
It's funny that you say you love me.
諦めの鼓動裏で鳴るハロー
A 'Hello' ringing behind a pulse of resignation.
混ざり合うハートは狂喜狂喜
Intertwining hearts in madness and ecstasy.
どこまでを許せばいいのかって
How much should I permit?
ぐるぐる回る妄想をわかって
Understand these spinning delusions.
頭の中を叩くアルト
The alto voice knocking in my head.
欲望の音はどっちどっち
Which one is the sound of desire?
ちぎれた僕振って大満足
Fully satisfied shaking my torn self.
腹が満たせりゃそれでいいだろ
If your stomach's full, that's enough, right?
ここにメインディッシュありますわ
I've got the main dish right here.
お口拭いておかわりはどうだい
Wipe your mouth; how about seconds?
あかんべのつづきとか
The continuation of 'Akanbe'...
思ったってやらんないのよ
Even if I think of it, I won't do it.
だって だって
Because, because...
虚しくなるだけだから
It would only lead to emptiness.
あかんべを覚えたら
Once you've learned 'Akanbe',
目一杯の笑顔になれるわ
You'll be able to smile to the fullest.
だって だって そうさ
Because, because, that's right...
僕は
I am...
あかんべで忘れましょう
Let's forget it with an 'Akanbe'.
正解はいらないのよ
I don't need the correct answer.
いいよ いいよ
It's fine, it's fine.
押し殺したげちゃうわ
I'll stifle it for you.
あかんべを覚えたら
Once you've learned 'Akanbe',
目一杯のドキドキしよう
Let's make our hearts pound to the max.
いいよ いいよ
It's fine, it's fine.
もっといい子になれたら開けましょう
If you can be a better kid, let's open up.
ねえねえ びっくりしちゃった？
Hey, hey, were you surprised?
もしかして怖くなっちゃった？
Did you maybe get scared?
嘘 全部なんちゃって
Lies, it's all just kidding.
驚かせてごめんね
Sorry for startling you.
ねえねえ びっくりしちゃった？
Hey, hey, were you surprised?
もしかして怖くなっちゃった？
Did you maybe get scared?
嘘 全部なんちゃって
Lies, it's all just kidding.
どちらが僕でしょうか
I wonder which one is me?
もう この深くで
Already, deep down here,
君は言葉を待っていたんだ
You were waiting for the words.
待っていたんだ 待っていたんだ
You were waiting, you were waiting.
倒れないように
So as not to fall,
伸ばした願いに
To the wish I reached out...
応えていくだけだよ 応えていくだけだよ
I'll just keep responding, I'll just keep responding.
与えることしかできないよ
I can only give.
隙間から見えた希望
The hope seen through the gaps.
空模様のように
Like the look of the sky
僕の色じゃなくても
Even if it's not my color
素敵に着こなせるよ
I can wear it beautifully
君の視界の僕は
In your field of vision, I am...
何の色に見えますか
What color do I look like to you?
張り巡らしたセンサーで
With my sensors spread all around
理由もなく好きになった
I fell in love with you for no reason
涙 お届けするから
Because I'll deliver tears to you
衣装を纏い 待っていて
Wear your costume and wait
風を切るまで
Until I cut through the wind
触れた顔に 触れることができたらいいのにな
If only I could touch the face I've touched
あたしの色は誰かの言葉 受け取るために花を咲かせるの
My color makes flowers bloom to receive someone's words
涙枯れたら 無限級数
When tears dry up, it's an infinite series
僕は目を開いて
I open my eyes
口を明け
And my mouth
息をしないで
Without breathing
色を呑む
I swallow the color
君は僕から何が見える？
What can you see from me?
って想像する心が欲しかった
I wanted a heart that imagines that
声を枯らすことのないように
So as not to lose my voice
僕にずっと色を注ぎ足してね
Keep adding colors to me forever
君の視界の僕は
In your field of vision, I am...
君の世界の僕を
How do you paint the me
どんな色に塗りますか
In your world?
季節に攫われるまでは
Until I'm carried away by the seasons
理由もなく手を
Without a reason, my hand...
涙を知りたいから
Because I want to know tears
衣装を纏う 五感をくれ
I'll wear a costume, give me five senses
側にいるほど 映る僕で
With the me reflected as much as I'm by your side
飾ることができたらいいのにな
If only I could decorate myself
湿っぽい季節の デコレーション グラデーション
Damp seasonal decorations, gradation
咲かせるための依存関係
A codependency for making things bloom
残しておいた余白で
With the margins I left behind
君の感覚を奪う
I'll steal your senses
生の本音はえぐいから
Since raw true feelings are harsh
ちゃんと火を通してから食べてね
Please eat them after they're properly cooked
嘘サービスはズルいから
Since fake services are unfair
それも維新のレシピ
That's also a recipe for restoration
みんな自分奪い合い
Is everyone scrambling for themselves?
嘘の晩餐会
A banquet of lies
みんな自分奪い合い
Is everyone scrambling for themselves?
痛みを手懐けて
Taming the pain
さあ 嫌いだけど好き 苦くても美味しい
Now, I hate it but I like it, it's bitter but delicious
着ぐるみを着て隠してあげる
I'll hide it for you by wearing a costume
泣かせないように 怒らせないように
So as not to make you cry or angry
ちょうどよく君と遊びたいのだ
I just want to play with you perfectly
猫かぶりの猫かぶりな
Neko kaburi, neko kaburi
ちょっと臆病な君が好き
I like you who's a bit cowardly
猫かぶりの猫かぶりな
Neko kaburi, neko kaburi
取り繕ってる僕が好き
I like me when I'm keeping up appearances
装ってる君が好きだよ
I like you when you're pretending
表と裏では大違い
There's a big difference between front and back
建前も本音も領地次第
Public stance and true feelings depend on the territory
みんな自分を疑っているかい
Is everyone doubting themselves?
独りぼっちの音楽隊
A lonely band
みんな自分を疑っているかい
Is everyone doubting themselves?
首輪の鈴鳴らして
Ring the bell on your collar
あー 災難だけどハッピー しんどくても平気
Ah, it's a disaster but happy, I'm fine even if it's tough
あべこべな夢を見せてあげる
I'll show you an upside-down dream
傷つけないように 追い詰めないように
So as not to hurt or corner you
夜明けまで君とふざけあうのだ
I'll mess around with you until dawn
猫かぶりの猫かぶりな
Neko kaburi, neko kaburi
爪を丸めてる君が好き
I like you with your claws rounded
猫かぶりの猫かぶりな
Neko kaburi, neko kaburi
涙を見せない僕が好き
I like me when I don't show tears
痛みを知ってる君が好きだよ
I like you who knows pain
もぐもぐ〜おかゆ〜！
Mogu mogu~ Okayu~!
みんな、今日は来てくれてありがとう！
Everyone, thank you for coming today!
ここからのね、『君は猫猫、パスなら好きの猫』の部分は、みんなにも一緒に歌ってほしいなと思って。
For the next part, "Kimi wa neko neko, pasu nara suki no neko," I want you all to sing along with me.
いい？『君は猫猫』って大きい声で歌うんだよ。
Okay? Sing "Kimi wa neko neko" in a loud voice.
行くよ？
Here we go!
せーの！
One, two!
君は猫、猫...
You are a cat, cat...
ネコ、ネコ、星月夜のネコ 君はヒト
Cat, cat, cat of the starry night, you are human.
ヒト、星月夜のヒト あれはUFO
Human, human of the starry night, that is a UFO.
UFO、星月夜のUFO 君はネコ
UFO, UFO of the starry night, you are a cat.
ネコ、ネコ、星月夜のネコ 君はヒト
Cat, cat, cat of the starry night, you are human.
ヒト、星月夜のヒト あれはUFO
Human, human of the starry night, that is a UFO.
UFO、星月夜のUFO 君はネコ
UFO, UFO of the starry night, you are a cat.
ネコ、ネコ、星月夜のネコ 君はヒト
Cat, cat, cat of the starry night, you are human.
ヒト、星月夜のヒト あれはUFO
Human, human of the starry night, that is a UFO.
UFO、星月夜のUFO 君は誰
UFO, UFO of the starry night, who are you?
誰、特別なヒト
Who? A special person.
猫被りの 猫被りの ちょっと臆病な君がすき
Feigning innocence, playing the cat, I like you, who's a little bit cowardly.
君も僕も 同じ名もない世界で
Both you and I, in the same nameless world,
やっと見つけた居場所だから
it's the place I've finally found.
猫被りの 猫被りの
Feigning innocence, playing the cat,
取り繕ってる僕が好き
I like myself, patching things up.
君も僕も どこか似てる世界で
Both you and I, in worlds that are somewhat similar,
明日もまた会えたらいいな
I hope we can meet again tomorrow.
猫被りの 猫被りの
Feigning innocence, playing the cat,
よそ見してる君が好きだよ
I like you, looking away.
3回目のもぐもぐ！
The third "Mogu Mogu"!
イェーイ！もうさ、3回ももぐもぐおかゆって言っちゃったよ
Yay! I've already said "Mogu Mogu Okayu" three times now.
このね、ライブの空気感でみんな僕が変なこと言ってもイェーイって言ってくれるからね
In this live atmosphere, even if I say something weird, everyone says "Yay!"
これですよ！ということでね、やっとこの日が来ました、横浜！
This is it! So, the day has finally come, Yokohama!
お邪魔しております
Thank you for having me.
いやー、もうさ、あっという間すぎたんだよこの時間まで
Man, time has just flown by until now.
さっきまで僕お弁当食べてたんだけど
I was eating a lunch box until just a moment ago.
で、食べるでしょ、お弁当
And you know, you gotta eat your lunch box.
僕の食べたお弁当は何お弁当でしょうか？
What kind of lunch box do you think I ate?
うん、なんて言ってるかよくわかんないけど
Yeah, I can't really tell what you're saying, but...
え、ちなみにさ、「おにぎり屋だよ」って人手挙げて！
By the way, raise your hand if you're an "Onigiri-ya"!
あー！最高最高！見えてるよありがとうね！
Ah! Great, great! I can see you, thank you!
ヤッホー！もちろんね、アリーナ席の
Yahoo! Of course,
配信チケットを見てるみんなも見えてるからね！
I can see everyone watching with streaming tickets, too!
イェーイ！
Yay!
ということでですね、皆さんなんとお気づきだと思いますが、
So, as I'm sure you've all noticed,
本日のバンドは生演奏となっております！
today's band is a live performance!
すごーい！
Amazing!
やっぱね、生演奏、お腹に来るよね、お腹に
As expected, a live performance really hits you in the stomach.
うわー来る、お腹に来るぞー！
Whoa, it's hitting! It's hitting my stomach!
僕のさっき食べたお弁当も多分フッフッてなってるわ
The lunch box I ate earlier is probably going "thump thump" inside me.
えー、あとですね、残念なお知らせがございます
Um, also, I have some sad news.
あ、これ定番だよね、もう一回やりたい、もう一回やりたい
Ah, this is a classic response, isn't it? I want to do it again, I want to do it again.
いくよ、ここで残念なお知らせがあります！
Here I go: I have some sad news!
なんと、冒頭無料チラ見せはここで終了です！
Believe it or not, the free sneak peek at the beginning ends here!
色を参考にしてみてください。
Please use the colors as a reference.
遠くて見えづらい人は...
For those who are too far away and find it hard to see...
あんまりね、大きな声じゃ言えないですけど...
I can't say this too loudly, but...
とりあえず紫にしとけば
If you just set it to purple for now,
間違いないから。
you can't go wrong.
間違いありません、本当に。
I'm not wrong, really.
ということで、
So,
今日は色んな表情の僕を楽しんでいってください！
please enjoy my many different expressions today!
では、次の曲いきましょう！
Now, let's move on to the next song!
無料パートは終了いたしました。ご視聴ありがとうございました！
The sneak peek part of the show has ended. Thank you for watching!
猫又おかゆ 2nd Live 「ぺるそにゃ～りすぺくと」
Nekomata Okayu 2nd Live: Persona Respect
無料パートは終了いたしました。ご視聴ありがとうございました！
The sneak peek part of the show has ended. Thank you for watching.